Guide to the Lou Henry Hoover House Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Lou Henry Hoover House Papers
1921-1949
SC0076B
Clark, Birge M. (Birge Malcolm), 1893-
0.25 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Birge M. Clark, 1970.
Information about Access
None.
BIOGRAPHY
Birge M. Clark (born 1893) was the son of Arthur B. Clark, who came to Stanford in 1892 as an Instructor in Drawing. Birge Clark received his A.B. from Stanford, 1914, and B.Arch from Columbia, 1917, and was an architect in Palo Alto. Both A. B. Clark and Birge Clark served as advising architects to Herbert and Lou Henry Hoover for their house on the Stanford campus.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
These papers consist primarily of correspondence between the Hoovers, Professor Clark, and Mr. Clark regarding planning and construction of the Lou Henry Hoover house; and sketches and specifications for the house. Part of the correspondence consists of copied materials from the Lou Henry Hoover papers in the Herbert Hoover Library (West Branch, Iowa), some of which concern Louis Mullgardt's plans for a house. Also included are materials used for and final edition of Mr. Clark's MEMOIRS ABOUT MR. AND MRS. HERBERT HOOVER, WITH PARTICULAR EMPHASIS ON THE PLANNING AND BUILDING OF THEIR HOME ON SAN JUAN HILL (Palo Alto: privately printed, 1969).
Access Terms
Clark, Arthur Bridgman, 1866-1948; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964; Hoover, Lou Henry, 1874-1944.; Lou Henry Hoover House (Stanford, Calif.)
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1921-1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1929-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous materials (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Material includes undated correspondence, sketches of portions of the house, "Specifications for the revised heating of the residence for Lou Henry Hoover.. .," xerox copies of newspaper clippings, and other assorted miscellany.
- Book: Memoirs about Mr. and Mrs. Herbert Hoover, with Particular Emphasis on the Planning and Building of their Home on San Juan Hill. By Birge M. Clark. Palo Alto, California., March 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Material used in Memoirs: tracings of the Hoover House. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Material used in Memoirs: Letters and pictures appearing within the text. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Numbered letters referred to in text of Memoirs. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Unnumbered letters, most of which appear in back of book. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence [copied from Lou Henry Hoover papers], 1917-Feb 1920 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence [copied from Lou Henry Hoover papers], 1920 March - 1922 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence [copied from Lou Henry Hoover papers], 1923- 1929 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence [copied from Lou Henry Hoover papers], 1930 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence [copied from Lou Henry Hoover papers], 1931- 1933 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence re Mullgardt plan [copied from Lou Henry Hoover papers], 1917, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 6)